hello
my name is green and oh my goodness it
is getting so close to christmas it's
unbelievable
anyway what i want to start off today by
what is that
what is this big red cube i've got to
check it out sorry
hold the intro what's going on here
this is uh
mumbo mumbo cube
ah there's an iscow
well okay then this server gets weirder
by the day i tell you what
at least that's not my island but we
will actually be doing a bit of work
here later on because what i think we
should do is make a train station
directly in the middle here
and this is going to be the stop that
accommodates for my base and mumbo's
base i actually want to do a lot of
things today so here's a little time
lapse of what i did during the in
between episodes things i finished off
making the ring around my base and it
didn't take too long it took about an
hour to finish that off and in the
future i'm definitely not going to
make something and then get rid of it
again so
it'll work down in the end and this is
the final product i have made sure that
it's equal all the way around i believe
there might be one or two mistakes
i think this looks really really cool to
the point where i actually want to
put together a little map i've got them
prepared here so why don't i put them
here so one two three four this is just
a temporary thing so one there one there
unfortunately it's not exactly centered
but it does the trick
now that looks really cool actually with
that
all the way around doesn't even look
like
holes in the ocean it wow that really
does have a nice effect
but that's just the beginning of what i
want to do in my base i actually think
that this ring needs a bit more as
everybody knows there's also been a lot
of stuff going on regarding the whole
hermitcraft feud prank war thing these
are the teams as they stand at the
moment this is going to be a lot of fun
to do now there's actually a few clips
later on explaining how we got to that
point because i'm actually recording a
little bit out of sync today but you'll
see later on how that all happened
however i would while we're building
like to just have a quick chat with
everybody about this whole uh prank war
kind of thing because there's some
things going on that i'm not too happy
about and it's nothing to do with the
other hermits so while i build this
bridge which is what i want to do here i
want to kind of make a bridge that goes
across here make it curve round i just
want to have a quick word about
the attitudes in the comments okay
because i think there's been probably a
bit of miscommunication
regarding this whole thing because this
is meant to be a whole lot of fun and
there's been a lot of nasty comments to
other hermits about them being traitors
to green or whatever
every single person on this server is my
friend whether they're on the other team
or not and it absolutely kills me i
can't stress this enough guys it
absolutely hurts me really deep down to
see my fans going on other people's
videos
and saying nasty things or calling them
traitors or whatever because we are
literally all friends here
we're just going to have a little bit of
fun and mayhem for once which we don't
normally do
and it's going to be an awful lot of fun
so in the future
while we're doing this big hermitcraft
feud thing i want to see nothing but
support for both teams
both teams
we're going to see some crazy pranks i
imagine over this this course of this
whole thing and to be honest with you it
doesn't matter who wins or who loses
because we're all friends and we're
meant to just be laughing at this whole
thing rather than getting all upset at
individual people every single person on
the other side of the team is my friend
and i hope to record with them just as
much as i record with my team over this
whole thing okay so that's enough of
that hopefully that sort of clears
things up we can all be really nice to
each other even though we're going to be
having a little bit of a kerfuffle i'm
really struggling with this i know i've
been like i look like i know what i'm
doing but i i really don't and what i
need to do is take a big step up in the
air
and try and plot this out in my mind but
the problem is when you look down when
you're flying around you tend to go
rather fast so i need to sort of edge
down i want it to go
no i'll see it it's too late for me now
maybe i need to go really high and then
make a decision
okay that's good and
right so i kind of need to make this go
a lot wider i think am i going to hit
i don't know why i didn't just dodge it
to be honest with you
didn't look like i was going to hit it i
thought it was gonna be close but i
didn't think i'd actually hit it oh geez
look at this mess this also means that
i'm going to have to replicate this
on both sides and i hope that that works
okay so i've done the first bridge i
haven't done any uh patterns or details
in it yet
however
oh that does look really nice i don't
even know if it needs two on each side
but the curvature on this is absolutely
fantastic
i'm i'm a little bit happy with that
actually i'm really pleased
do you think it needs a bit of glass i
think it might do think it might need a
little bit of glass how on earth where
have you come from
i thought i got rid of all of these
ah jeez how did it get up there
anyway that looks really nice the
curvature goes all the way it kind of
connects up nicely
now i could do like a circle here or
just another one that
i don't know kind of looks nice just all
in block color
this is a tricky one i might experiment
with it a little bit or maybe do a small
i think i'm gonna do a small triangle i
think that's what i'm gonna do so not
all the way through but a small triangle
here now you know what i'm actually
really happy at the moment because
i was getting a really bored of building
my base like really bored so i'm super
happy to have a bit of fire and passion
again for building this thing because
this is such an enormous project like
thousands and thousands of blocks that
were manually collected went into this
whole thing and
i don't know just something about it
after a while i started going like oh
what am i gonna do but since we've had
like a break with all of this prank
stuff going on
it's actually really refreshing to get
back to a bit of building that actually
does look really cool it's like an
arrowhead there if i put another one
here that looks super futuristic
that does actually remind me that this
place needs
some anti-spawning mechanisms where did
they go oh they're just
nope
[Laughter]
yeah that was great
wait wait wait
come on
i don't have to do anything
that is a brilliant mechanic is he
actually i've got to get the kill right
oh that was fantastic
i actually have a couple of things to do
other than building in my base which is
the main focus of today's episode i do
want to get lots of progress on because
it it does seem like there's just not
been much change recently and i want to
fix that however i did commit to doing
the secret santa and i pulled out
iskall's name and it says that he's been
naughty now iskall is on my team but
if he's been naughty this year then he's
got to get some coal but you see coal is
really useful so i think i've got
something else in mind for him several
revisions later it has i think been
perfected looks pretty good there's
still a lot of white concrete there so
maybe it does need something extra but
that shape is just really nice i think
maybe it's actually this here that is
outdated because i've sort of
come up with this pattern as i've gone
along and i didn't actually put anything
around here so there's a lot more glass
here than i think there maybe should be
like there's a lot of outlining going on
over there but not on the inside so
perhaps there's a a bit of tinkering
need to be done there but i've spent
about an hour on this bridge now so i'm
pretty sick of it already but i'll come
back to it another time i've got
everything that i need to build my
little secret santa for iska which
actually took me a while to collect isco
is afk and the only other person on is
false so
let's just hope that he's not here
somewhere if he's here we've got a
problem if he's afk and his base
somewhere then we're fine
okay let's give it a go basically
because iskal got a naughty he got the
naughty thing for his secret santa i'm
going to encase his gift in a coal of
diorite because coal if i just gave him
some coal
it's a well it's actually kind of useful
in minecraft you see he could use that
for his furnaces
but diorite diorite is something that he
absolutely hates so if i make a coal
made of diorite he's got to break into
this to get his gift now it is christmas
so even though he's been naughty he's
still going to get a little bit of a fun
present because i don't i really want to
just give him rubbish because he's been
naughty all year we all know that he
hasn't really he just got bad luck when
i picked the two pieces of paper so he
got a 50 50 chance either way he's gonna
hate the fact that there's a big blob of
dior right here because it looks a
little bit like bird poop there we go
now all i need to do is stick in here a
shulker box i did not need nearly as
much diorite as i thought so what i've
done is i've given him stuff that is
annoying to craft every time you need
this sort of thing in minecraft you're
like oh because the crafting recipe is
so annoying to get and you need to so
many different things so there's pistons
comparators observers and repeaters and
then there's three puffer fish which i'm
hoping will become very useful
in the little prank war that is going on
i can't believe i'm perfecting a blob of
diorite but there we are so i've written
here iscao i was your secret santa this
year and you were naughty so you got a
lump of diorite sorry from g and then i
put just kidding i can't leave with
can't leave you with nothing at
christmas so he's got a gift but he's
also got a lump of coal i think that's a
pretty nice compromise there i don't
want to give him just rubbish but also
poultry man who is my um
my friend my my roommate he shares my
base with me he actually got uh one as
well and he's told me that he has
already delivered his secret santa so
whatever that may be
no oh what
oh
man
i forgot about mending my elytra
whoa
what is that about
why is there tnt outside every single
portal
what
press me jingled
the jingle is at it again
i kinda wanna i kinda want to
i kind of want to
i can't help it i'm sorry
it did nothing it did one block of
damage
unbelievable it doesn't matter by the
way about blowing all this stuff up
because in this giant nether project
that we're doing this uh it's all got to
go everything in here has got to go oh i
forgot i've got elytra oh no
i'm so used to having electric
i think the problem here is that there's
not enough glass there's too much
white concrete and not nearly enough
glass
so i think that's gonna need even more
revision maybe if i extend it out and
then do make it connect up oh this is
so confusing however i do actually want
to start a project up here by creating a
little avery but there's no point in
creating an avery if i don't have any
birds
so i've got a bit of a conundrum on my
hands i need to go and get some parrots
from somewhere
so i've arranged to meet up with
everybody on my side at the moment to
see if we can form some kind of team so
let's go and do that right now hello
everybody i have called you here today
around this
rather doomsday looking map that iskall
put together
to bring up a major issue
on the server right now so as you can
see iskall has put together
a little list of heads here that
represent every hermit on the server
and in the middle we have neutral
players on the right we have their team
i don't know what their team is called
but their team it has impulse bren doc
false and x on it
and we all kind of know our own reasons
for them to be on that team there's been
a series of pranks going on and because
of a series of events that have led us
to get together our team on this side
everyone here including tango who's not
here but we're gonna we're gonna make
him here anyway so hold on hey guys
tango's here as well
how are you doing what are you doing
oh yeah okay so
is everyone in agreement here that we
are allies and we are absolutely a team
against
them
yep
one condition one condition we need a
super super sweet team name yes
i mean i don't know what their team name
is we could wait to hear what theirs is
and then like make an opposite one
although i did have a pretty sweet idea
yeah here let me let me see what you
think i suggest the g team okay now hear
me out you're all thinking oh what's
that all about well everyone here has a
g in their name green tango
see it all works right
zombie glio
grass monster
go hills
hi gavin it works so well oh yeah i
gotta say it really rolls off the tongue
yeah
i'm liking it
it's rememberable
in your logic
what do you mean i don't know what
you're talking about what's that about
zombie glio
and the the added bonus here right is
that we can like we can like enter enter
the headquarters and be like what's up g
it works so well i agree gria this is a
really good idea see tango agrees so we
all need to decide where we're going to
make our base okay does anybody have any
ideas and
um
no you've been here the whole time dude
this is the war room dude so we're a
team now we're a team we're the g team
we can't put any of our own bases on the
line we need a group project which will
take the hits
from the other team
that's the idea we need to have a safe
place where we store all our stuff we
have our operations etc
and we can get the other team quite
easily so i have a little place in mind
should we all fly over there and start
setting up shop
see if it's good
jevin you look awfully close to that
chicken dude like
oh i'm not a poultry
that on me
don't put that on me
don't don't give me that hate no anyway
this is the location i was thinking
because this is like a super undeveloped
part of the island no one's using this
and i think like this would work really
well
what we're going to call it ghq
i think what we could do to mark our
location is like should we build like a
flag here just to show that yes
all right there we go very simple flag
but it's marked so this is where we're
going to start building our headquarters
and
we're going to win this feud this this
kerfuffle this this
this could buffle with the other team so
the g team has officially been put
together
the plan right now is to go and get
myself a bunch of parrots and
this isn't gonna be fun i i've never
done this before
and i i don't really know what i'm doing
i think i give them seeds and then they
love me and then they sit on my
shoulders but i don't think i can fly so
i've even brought a boat with me i just
need to find a jungle and i remember
that there's one around here somewhere
yeah this is gonna be annoying all right
now we've just got to find a couple of
what on earth why is there a big fire in
gold
what the heck is this
have i found something
it's like a broken airship
with cake
and convex
what is this
i hope i'm not spoiling something but
what is this is there some sort of
secret to find it there's like a cage
this is
weird
really weird maybe one of you guys knows
what this is because it's really
confusing it doesn't seem to be anything
for me to get
there's actually a plate here
nothing this is super strange but the
fact that there's a cage in the same
same style as like the guinea pig green
thing
that is really weird anyway i was
looking for parrots where are they
maybe i gotta fly around there we go
there we go there we have our first
parrot friend
nom nom
nom nom nom nom nom nom nom nom nom nom
nom nom nom nom nom are you gonna go
through a stack of seeds jeez okay now
you're my friend now what
sit
not sit
are you gonna go on are you gonna sit on
my shoulder is that how this works
come on come on little fella
on my shoulder are you gonna follow me
at least
look i can make you like do the little
dum dum dum dum dum dum dum dum dum dum
dum dum dum i am a little bird but
that's got to be sitting obviously now
he's not sitting
does he just follow me wherever i go
oh yes he does
it happened
oh my goodness this is so cute
so i i don't know how to get them back
to my base
because i think as soon as i jump
yep he gets off
i don't know how to do this because
every time i fly
oh there they are oh my my friends okay
we're missing we're missing a few
but most of you are here does that mean
what if i just fly around and
can i get most of them to teleport back
there they all are i think that's
everybody
okay so now all i need to do is
slowly make my way back and get these
guys to teleport i think that's the way
forward i think i've got enough and i'm
happy with who i found green guy three
blue guys and a red guy
now how do i get back to my base oh
what's going on
this is the best day of my life
i love animals so much
this took a long time
but i've managed to get them all the way
back to the base
oh this is exciting i can't wait to make
these guys a little home this is going
to be like my tranquility room i guess
like it's going to be a place for these
guys to sit in and for it's like my safe
place my happy place and they're all
here okay so let's bring them inside
hopefully they'll tp down here yes and
now all we gotta do is get them all to
sit nicely and you guys are just gonna
creep me out with a load of creeper
sounds for a very long time now i only
have one name tag so
i've got to choose one bird and i'm
gonna name them after everybody's
favorite bird
ari
but the question is is it of the blue
one or are they a little bit green
i don't really
ari's got to be more of a bluey green
i'm gonna go with you you are now ari
everybody's favorite verb in the whole
wide world on youtube that is and i
think that's pretty much what we're
going to have to start working on in the
next episode because this is actually
going to be a pretty big project to fill
this full of greenery so i'll get
started with the basic stuff you know
putting in some grass and stuff maybe it
could even like slope down steadily
until it reaches here so it would kind
of go like that and it'd be like a bowl
shape so maybe i'll go for something
like that but now
to kind of finish off this episode we
need to go and meet up with absolutely
everybody on the server that has been
involved in some kind of pranking
because the teams have been made and we
need to sort of set in some rules so
let's go and do that right now
well
well well
what have we gotten ourselves into i
think
we can all agree
that things on this server have gotten
far too out of hand we have put up a
giant white flag to symbolize
that there is a ceasefire right now no
more pranks no more fighting because we
need to sort some things out before we
get into all of this mess all over again
okay so on this side we got the g team
wait
joe
wrong side bro over here well i don't
know what i'm doing what are you guys
called
so you guys have already started making
a headquarters and
admittedly we were behind you and we've
started headquarters over there which
yeah again admittedly is only a flag
before we get into this proper kerfuffle
we need to lay down a few ground rules
okay
because otherwise this whole thing could
destroy the entire server and nobody
wants that we need to settle our
differences
with honor okay
right so first thing we're not going to
totally annihilate each other's bases
with tnt it's so easy to do i know but
we're not going to do that in this
all right it's only micro annihilations
yeah only small micro annihilations okay
small okay keep it lit keep it keep it
low all right there's going to be a
cease fire okay we need time to build
our bases i mean it's been a few days
and all we've got is a flag so we're
going to need a few more days to build a
bigger flag
so they're going to be a ceasefire until
after the new years to give us a good
amount of time to build up our bases our
headquarters everyone okay with that
that means
no trapping no fighting no pranking
until this flag in the middle comes down
and the other thing is we're going to
keep this war in the boundary between
our base over there with the red flag
and your base the star for over there
we've got to keep it centralized because
if this
spills over poor tfc is going to have
his bunker destroyed and no one wants to
see that okay stealing is a-okay
trapping your headquarters and their
headquarters is a-okay
and lethal pranking is okay all right
those are the three other things are we
ready to get our bases set up 100 50 i
can't wait
oh wow
stand back from doc yeah don't don't go
near you just couldn't think of it a
thunderstorm
[Laughter]
what did i just say cease fire ceasefire
ceasefire
you guys go through my stick go go make
your base off you go doodle pitch
no more no more fighting
ceasefire so i'm afraid that's all we
have time for in today's episode we've
made a load of progress in
the base and i'm pretty happy with how
things are going i need to make some
serious alterations to that bridge which
i spent over two hours on because it's
still not right it doesn't match the
rest of the base yet but it'll get there
in the end and i'd also like to
reiterate the point that i made earlier
on in this episode that it would be
really cool and it means a lot to me if
everyone shows everybody support in this
this weird scuffle fuffle kerfuffle
whatever you want to call it between all
the hermits because it's meant to be a
lot of fun it's we don't actually
have any sort of uh malicious feelings
for each other we love each other we are
really good friends on this server we
just want to have a little bit of mayhem
and a little bit of fun as well so make
sure that you don't take it too
seriously and have a lot of fun with it
okay thank you very much everyone and
i'll see you in the next episode good
bye and have a good christmas too